Finding aid for the St. Xavier College academic medals collection
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections
St. Xavier College academic medals collection
1887-1988
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections Phone: 513-745-4821 http://www.xavier.edu/cm/archives
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio)
.5 linear feet (1 box)
This is a collection of academic medals awarded between the years 1887 and 1909 to St. Xavier College students Henry B. Poetker, Albert H. Poetker and Peter E. Dempsey. The collection includes some accompanying notes.
XUA- 39
Biography of Biography or History
These medals were given to recognize student academic accomplishments at St. Xavier College, Cincinnati, Ohio.The presentation of the awards in this collection are documented in the St. Xavier course catalogs for the periods concerned. Most of the medals (6) were awarded to Albert H. Poetker who later became a Jesuit priest, taught at Xavier University, and later became president of the University of Detroit.
Scope and Content
Eight academic medals awarded for various accomplishments. Included with the collection is one typeset "X" block letter.
Statement of Arrangement
The collection is mainly arranged into folders by the year of award presentation, beginning with 1887 and concluding with 1909.
Acquisition Information
The Poetker medals were given to Xavier University by Miss Rose M. Poetker in 1980, the Sesquitennial Year of Xavier University.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects:
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio)--Medals; Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio)--Students
Persons:
Poetker, Albert H., 1887-1960--Medals; Poetker, Henry B.--Medals; Dempsey, Peter E.--Medals
Detailed Description of The Collection
- Medal: Dempsey Prize Catechetical Essay, 1887 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Medal: Poetker, Albert H. Honors, Third Academic, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Medal: Poetker, Albert H. Honors, Class of 1902, Second Academic (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Medal: Poetker, Albert H. Catechetical Prize Medal, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Medal: Poetker, Albert H. Philosophy Class, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Medal: Poetker, Albert H. Catechetical Prize Medal, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Medal: Poetker, Albert H. Class of Poetry, Division B, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Medal: Poetker, Henry B. Honors of First Year Class, Division B, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Typeset "X" Block Letter, undated, 1920? (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Collection Notes, 1980-1988; undated (Box 1, Folder 10)